如果你把从人类历史早期
If you take all human data
到 2003 年创造的所有数据计算在内
created from the dawn of time to 2003
你将得到大约 500 万 GB 的数据
you'd get about five million gigabytes of data
我们昨天创造了多少 GB 数据
How many gigabytes of data did we create yesterday
哦 天哪
Oh gosh
10 万
100,000
可能是 500 万 GB 数据
Like five million gigabytes
How many gigabytes of data did we create yesterday
我们在昨天一天之内创造了多少 GB 的数据
in one day? 10 million gigabytes?
一千万 GB？
我不太知道 可能是
I would say, I don't know, like
200 万 GB 数据
two million maybe
也许一天就有 100 万 GB 数据
Maybe a million gigabytes in a day
答案是 超过 25 亿 GB 数据
Answer? More than 2.5 billion
哇哦
Oh wow. Wow.
25 亿? 对的 25 亿
2.5 billion? Billion!
哇哦
Oh wow. Wow.
25 亿? 对的 25 亿
2.5 billion? Billion!
所以 我们已经打破了世界纪录
So, we already beat the world record
25 亿? 对的 25 亿
2.5 billion? Billion!
那可真是很多个 G 啊
That's a lot of gigabytes
我都不敢相信那有这么多的数据
That's a lot of data right there. I don't believe it.
在 2016 年 我们的年度在线数据流量
In 2016, our annual data traffic online
首次超过了 1ZB
passed one zetabyte for the first time
一个 ZB 是 1000^7 字节
That's one sextillion bytes
好 记住这个数字了吗
if it helps. Okay, got that number in your head?
现在把它乘以 3
Now triple it
因为那是我们将在 2021 年拥有的数据量
because that's how much data we'll have by 2021
我知道 大脑不是以 ZB 为单位进行思考的
I know, the brain wasn't made to think in zetabytes
但请你至少暂时记住这个数
but just hold onto this one little fact for a second
我们的 IP 流量将在五年内翻三番
Our IP traffic will triple in five years
注：这里的 IP 指 TCP/IP 中的 IP，而非知识产权和品牌相关的概念
这是数据的洪流 而我们正处于其中
It's a data flood and we're in the middle of it
在刚过去的一分钟里
That last minute that went by
人们发出了 1600 万条短信
people sent 16 million text messages
与此同时 在我说出这句话的时间里
and in the time it took me to say that sentence
谷歌处理了 20 万条搜索
Google processed 200,000 searches
如果我们能在数据洪流来临时
Hidden inside that data flood are patterns
*这部分的语序在翻译时遭到了调整，因此中文和英文文本无法一句句对应。
做好准备 站稳脚跟
answers, and secrets
*这部分的语序在翻译时遭到了调整，因此中文和英文文本无法一句句对应。
那么隐藏在其中的模式、答案和秘密可以
that can massively improve our lives
*这部分的语序在翻译时遭到了调整，因此中文和英文文本无法一句句对应。
那么隐藏在其中的模式、答案和秘密可以
if we can just keep ourselves standing upright
*这部分的语序在翻译时遭到了调整，因此中文和英文文本无法一句句对应。
极大地改善我们的生活
when the flood comes in
*这部分的语序在翻译时遭到了调整，因此中文和英文文本无法一句句对应。
我是 Saron Yitbarek 这里是《代码英雄》
I'm Saron Yitbarek and this is Command Line Heroes
一款红帽公司原创的播客节目
an original podcast from Red Hat
浪潮近在眼前
The tidal waves are on the horizon
这里是第二季第六集 数据大爆炸
This is episode 6 of season 2, the data flood
我们如何处理如此大量的数据
So, how do we handle such enormous amounts of data
采集到这些数据后 我们如何利用它们
How will we make use of that data once it's captured
大数据将为我们解决一些最复杂的问题
Big data is going to solve some of our most complicated problems
如何管理交通 如何种植粮食
How we manage traffic, how we grow food
如何向需要的人提供物资
How we deliver supplies to those in need
但这一切的前提是 我们必须弄清楚该怎么使用这些数据
But only once we figure out how to work with all that data
以及该怎么在短得不能再短的时间内完成对它们的处理
how to process it, and at breakneck speed
通过获取更多的数据
By having more data
我们可以深入到这些子群体
we can drill down into these sub-groups
这些细节 而这是
these particulars, and these details
我们以前从来没有过的方式
in ways that we never could before
Kenneth Cukier 是《经济学人》的高级编辑
Kenneth Cukier is a senior editor at The Economist
他也是科技播客《Babbage》的主持人
and he's also the Saron Yitbarek of their tech podcast called Babbage
这并不是说我们以前无法收集数据 我们可以
It's not to say that we couldn't collect the data before. We could
但这真的 真的很昂贵
it just was really, really expensive
真正的革命性突破是 我们使数据搜集
The real revolution is that we can collect this data
变得十分容易 现在收集数据的成本极低
very easily. It's very inexpensive
而且处理起来也超级简单
and the processing is super simple
因为都是由电脑完成的
because it's all done by a computer
这已经成为我们这个时代的巨大革命
This has become the huge revolution of our era
它可能是现代生活
and it is probably the most defining
最显著的特征
aspect of modern life
在未来几十年甚至下个世纪都会如此
and will be for the next several decades, if not the next century
这也是大数据如此重要的原因
That's why big data's such a big deal
历史可以提醒我们 这种变化是翻天覆地的
A little history can remind us how radical that change has been
想想看 4000 年前
Think about it, 4,000 years ago
我们把所有的数据都刻在了干泥板上
we were scratching all our data into dried slabs of mud
这些泥板很重
These clay disks were heavy
泥板被烤干后 刻在其中的数据
The data that is imprinted in them once they're baked
就无法更改 从古至今
can't be changed. All of these features
信息处理
of how information was
存储 传输 创建的方式
processed, stored, transferred, created
都发生了变化 对吗
has changed, right
时代巨变 大约在 1450 年
Changed big time. Around the year 1450
印刷机的发明
you get the first information revolution
带来了第一次信息革命
with the invention of the printing press
今天 我们也迎来了一场革命
And today, we have our own revolution
现在的存储介质很轻巧
It's lightweight
信息的修改变得极度简单 借助现有的处理器
It can be changed super simply because we can just use
我们只需要使用删除键就能修改我们所拥有的信息实例
the delete key and change the instantiation of the information that we have
无论那是储存在磁带上
in whether it's the magnetic tape or in the transition of the electronic
还是晶体管的变化里
transistors and the processors that we have
我们可以以光速传输数据
We can transport it at the speed of light
不用携带什么泥板
unlike say a clay disk that you have to carry
在 15 世纪 借助印刷机 大量的数据得以传播
The printing press levelled up our understanding of things
这些知识提升了人们对事物的认识 并促成了启蒙运动
with the 15th-century flood of data that ushered in the enlightenment
今天 大数据可以再次提升我们的知识水平
Today, big data can level us up again
但我们必须要想办法充分利用这些数据
But only if we figure out how to take advantage of all that data
唯有修好大坝 备好轮机
Only if we build the dams and the turbines
才能让浪潮为人所用
that will put the flood to work
当下 人们远没有做到
There is a huge gap between what is possible
对数据的充分利用
and what companies and individuals and organizations are doing
这一点非常重要 因为我们已经看到
That's really important because we could already see
数据中存在这种潜在的价值
that there's this latent value in the data
而收集 存储和处理数据的成本
and that the cost of collecting, storing, and processing the data
在近百年来 乃至于近十年来
has really dropped down considerably to where it was
已经显著地降低了
of course, a hundred years ago but even just ten years ago
这很振奋人心 但问题是 我们在文化上
That's really exciting. But the problem is that, culturally
在我们的组织流程上
and in our organizational processes
甚至我们的 CFO 和 CIO 们拨给
and even in the budgets that our CFOs and our CIOs
相关方面的预算中 并不重视这种价值
allot to data, we're not there yet
想着这种事肯定让人极度沮丧
Super frustrating when you think about it
启蒙运动在敲门 却无人应答
Enlightenment knocking at the door and nobody's answering
然而 我们不回答的部分原因是
Part of the reason we're not answering though
门后到底是谁
is that, well, who's actually behind the door
这些数据能带来什么
What's all this data gonna deliver
Kenneth 认为 某些公司不采用大数据
Kenneth figures the newness of big data
乃是因为它太过于新奇
keeps some companies from taking that leap
一旦你收集了大量数据后 你能拿它干什么
What is the value of the data once you collect a lot of it
我就直说吧
The most honest answer is
只有傻子才会以为自己知道
if you think you know, you're a fool
你绝对无法设想你今天
Because you can never identify today
收集到的数据明天能拿来做什么用
all the ways with which we're going to put the data to uses tomorrow
重点在于要把数据攥在手里
The most important thing is to have the data
并以开放的思想对待所有可以使用的方式
and to have an open mind in all the ways that it can be used
如果我们按照 Kenneth 说的那样 以正确的方式对待大数据
What Kenneth's envisioning if we get big data right
我们将会发现一切的全新可能性
is a wholesale transformation of our attitudes towards what's possible
等待我们的将是一个人人 - 而不只是数据科学家
A world where everybody, not just data scientists
都能洞察趋势、分析细节的世界
can see the potential and gain insight
如果我们能意识到 这个世界是
By understanding that the world is one
可以通过收集经验证据
in which we can collect empirical evidence about it
来理解、改变和改善的
in order to understand it, and in order to change it, and improve it
并且可以用一种自动化的方式进行改善
and that improvements can happen in an automated fashion
我们将会得到看待它的全新角度
we will see the world in a different way
我个人认为 现如今 在世界各地
and I think that's the really interesting change that's happening now
上至政策制定者 、下至星巴克咖啡师
culturally or psychologically around the world where
都在经历这种引人深思的文化上或心理上的变化
policy makers and business people and Starbucks baristas
各行各业的人都有点数据基因
Everyone in all walks of life sort of have the data gene
就像是被感染了似的 现在
They got it. They've sort of gotten the inoculation and now
无论他们专注于什么方面 他们都以大数据的方式思考
everywhere they look, they think in a data mindset
Kenneth Cukier 给我们讲了一个简短的故事来展现
Kenneth Cukier told us a quick story to illustrate
这种新数据思维方式的力量
the power of that new data mindset
微软的一些研究人员开始着手研究胰腺癌问题
Some researchers at Microsoft began thinking about pancreatic cancer
人们发现胰腺癌往往为时已晚
People often find out about pancreatic cancer too late
早期发现可以挽救生命
and early detection could save lives
因此 研究人员开始询问这些患者
So, the researchers began asking
在开始搜索有关胰腺癌的信息之前几个月
before these patients start searching for information on pancreatic cancer
他们搜索了什么
what were they searching for in the previous few months
而早在发现前数年 他们又搜索了什么 研究人员开始
And in the previous years. They began looking for clues
寻找埋藏在所有
buried inside all that search data
搜索数据中的线索和模式
They began looking for patterns
他们有了重大发现 通过分析患者在最终开始搜索“胰腺癌”
They struck pay dirt. They saw that they can identify patterns in the search terms
之前的这段时间中所搜索的关键词 他们识别出了一套规律
leading up to the moment where people started searching for pancreatic cancer
可以非常准确地预测搜索者是否患有胰腺癌
that predicted very accurately that people had pancreatic cancer
在这里，我们能学到一点：想象力与
The lesson here is that by using their imagination in terms of
数据中潜在规律的结合 是可以挽救生命的
the latent knowledge inside of data, they can save lives
他们现在所要做的就是找到一种方法
All they need now to do is to find a way to instrument
通过方法来解释这一发现
through policy this finding
这样当人们在搜索这些术语时
so that when people are searching for these terms
他们可以以一种微妙的方式干预 说
they can intervene in a subtle way to say
“你可能要去诊所检查一下”
You might wanna go to a healthcare clinic and get this checked out
像这样使用数据 就能救人于水火之中
If they start doing that, people's lives will be saved
研究人员偶然发现的是一种新的癌症筛查方式
What the researchers stumbled upon is a new form of cancer screening
通过这种方法 患者可以提前一个月得知自己可能患癌
a process that could alert patients month earlier
利用数据不仅仅是一个利润或效率最大化的问题
Making use of data isn't just a question of maximizing profits or efficiency
它的意义远不止于此
It's about so much more than that
对于人类而言 这些数据中确确实实存在着大量的潜在利好
Hiding in all that data are real, enormous positives for humankind
抗拒使用大数据可能只是自欺欺人
If we don't use that data, we could be cheating ourselves
接下来 我们要关注的是
It's that epic struggle to put data to work
这场将数据投入工作的持久战
that we're focusing on next
哈佛医学院的波士顿儿童医院
Boston Children's Hospital at Harvard Medical School
去年完成了 26000 多台手术
performed more than 26,000 surgeries last year
进行约 25 万人次的
Kids walk through their doors
儿童放射检查
for about a quarter million radiological exams
医护人员的表现令人称道
The staff is doing incredible work
但有一个巨大的障碍挡在他们面前
but there's a huge roadblock standing in their way
在医院的环境中 尤其是
A lot of the problems that we have in a hospital environment
作为医生 我们经常会遇到难以获取数据的问题
especially as a physician, is how to get access to the data
这位是 Ellen Grant 医生
That's Dr. Ellen Grant
她是波士顿儿童医院的儿科神经放射科医生
She's a pediatric neuroradiologist at Boston Children's
她在诊疗时依靠访问数据和分析医学图像
and she depends on accessing data and analyzing medical images
如果没有专门设置的环境
It's not simple to get access into
想要对 PACS 存档里存储的图像进行
say a PACS archive where the images are stored
额外的数据分析绝非易事
to do additional data analysis unless you set up an environment and that's
当你在一个只提供了普通的医院电脑的读片室里时
not easy to do when you're in a reading room where there are just
要做到这一点并不容易
standard hospital PCs provided
获取数据实际上是有障碍的
There's a barrier to actually get to the data
其实许多医院都会大量抛弃数据
Hospitals actually dump a lot of their data
因为存储它们的成本实在过于高昂
because they can't afford to store it
这部分数据就像这样丢失了
So, that data's just lost
像 Grant 这样的放射科医生可能是第一批
Radiologists like Dr. Grant may have been the first group of doctors
因为数据实在太多而感到沮丧的医务人员
to feel the frustration of data overload
当医院走向数字化后 他们开始创造大量的数据
When they went digital, they began creating enormous amounts of data
很快 这个量就大到无法处理了
and that quickly became impossible to handle
我 作为一名临床医生 在读片室里的时候
I, as a clinician, in the reading room
希望能将所有复杂的分析工作在研究环境中做完
wanted to be able to do all the fancy analysis that could be done in a research environment
但我无法随便就从 PACS 中拿出来图像
But there's no way to easily get images off of the PACS
拿到一些可以进行分析的地方
and get them to some place where the analysis could be done
再拿回到我手里
and get them back into my hands
顺便说一句 PACS 就是医院存储其图像的数据仓库
PACS by the way are what hospitals call the data banks that store their images
Grant 医生知道有一些工具
Dr. Grant knew there were tools
可以让这些保存图像的 PACS 发挥更大的功能
that could make those PACS of images more functional
但成本太高
but costs were prohibitive
随着机器学习和 AI 时代的到来
As we're entering into this era of machine learning and AI,
数据的生产量将会日渐加大
there's more of that gonna happen
我们会需要更多计算资源来进行这类
that we need these larger computational resources to really start to do
大规模的数据库分析
the large database analysis we wanna do
数据已经堆积如山了
The data's been piling up
但处理能力却没有相称的增长
but not so much the processing
在这一前提下 对数据的彻底处理将变得遥不可及
On premise data processing would be out of reach
而复杂 昂贵的超级计算机
And elaborate, expensive supercomputers
并不是医院的选择
aren't an option for hospitals
Grant 医生深感沮丧
Dr. Grant became deeply frustrated
我们能不能想出一个更好的办法 让我把数据拿到这里来
Can't we figure out a better way for me to just get data over here
分析一下 然后放回去 这样我就可以
analyze it, get it back so I can do it
在会诊的时候 一边解释临床图像 一边把分析做完
at the console where I'm interpreting clinical images
因为我希望可以在会诊上展示数据
cause I wanna have that data
在此同时进行快速分析 我可不想在
there and analyzed there quickly, I don't wanna have to
在不同的电脑之间挪来挪去 记住所有的代码
move to different computers and memorize all this line code
这不是我的工作 我的工作是
when that's not my job. My job is
理解非常复杂的医学疾病 并把
trying to understand very complex medical diseases and
相关的事实真相记在脑子里 我想
keep all those facts in my head. So I wanted to
我想专注于我的技术领域 在此同时
keep my focus on where my skill set was but exploit
利用计算机领域的新兴技术 而不必过于深入钻研
what is emerging in the computational side without having to dive that deep into it
Grant 和世界各地的放射科医生们需要的是一种方法
What Dr. Grant and radiologists around the world
只要点击图像就能运行详细分析
needed was a way to click on imagery run detailed analysis
并让这一切都发生在云端
and have it all happen on the cloud
这样医院就不必建立自己的服务器场地
so the hospital didn't have to build their own server farm
也不必把医务人员变成程序员
and didn't have to turn the medical staff into programmers
他们需要一种方法来使他们的数据尽可能地拯救生命
They needed a way to make their data save all the lives it could
这正是 Grant 医生
and so, that's exactly what Dr. Grant
和几位代码英雄决定去做的事
and a few command line heroes decided to build
Grant 在波士顿儿童医院的团队
Dr. Grant's team at Boston Children's Hospital
正在与红帽和马萨诸塞州开放云（MOC）合作
worked with Red Hat and the Massachusetts Open Cloud (MOC)
关于 MOC 的更多内容稍后再说
More on the MOC a little later
首先 我们需要请出 Rudolph Pienaar
First though, here's Rudolph Pienaar
他是医院的一名生物化学工程师
a biomedical engineer at the hospital
来描述一下他们的解决方案
describing their solution
它是一个开源的、基于容器的成像平台
It's an open source, container-based imaging platform
它完全是在云端运行的
It's all run on the cloud, too
所以你不受医院本身计算能力的限制
So you're not limited by the computing power at the hospital itself
他们称这一作品为 ChRIS
They call their creation ChRIS
ChRIS 有一个后台数据库 其实就是一个 Django Python 机器
There's a backend database that's a Django Python machine really
它可以跟踪用户
and that keeps track of users
并跟踪这些用户使用过的数据以及分析结果
It keeps track of the data they've processed. It keeps track of results
围绕这个数据库  有大量的服务群
Then there are a whole bunch of constellation of services around this database
这些服务都是作为独立的实例存在于容器中
that all exist as their own instances in containers
它们处理与医院资源的通信
These deal with communicating with hospital resources like databases
比如与医院数据库的通信
They deal with, you know
这些服务从资源中提取复杂的数据
the intricacies of pulling data from these resources and then
将其推送给云端的 或者另一个实验室的
pushing them out to other services that exist on a cloud
或者别的什么地方的其他服务处理
or another lab or whatever it might be
在计算数据的地方
On the place where data is computed
有 Kubernetes 之类的编排服务
there's all these services like Kubernetes
以及你需要使用的分析程序
the schedule, the actual analysis of the data that you want to be doing
数据处理结束之后 结果就会被发送回来
Then, pulling it back again
对于 Grant 医生来说 ChRIS 成像平台
For Dr. Grant, the ChRIS imaging platform
是一种让数据活起来的方法
is a way to make data come to life
更重要的是 这种数据处理方式能让她成为更好的医生
More than that, it's a way for data to make her a better doctor
优秀的医生之所以优秀 是因为
What makes a person a good physician is the
他们在一生中积累了丰富的从业经验
experience they've had over a lifetime of practicing
如果我们能把这一点融入到
But if I can kind of embody that into the
数据分析中 以此来获得更多的信息
data analysis and access more of that information
我们就能知道得更多
we just all know more and can
并更有效地整合这些经验 例如
combine the information better. So for example
我对特定病患的特定受伤方式的认识
I have a perception of what a certain
pattern of injury looks like in a certain patient population
取决于我的从医经验和对这些经验的整体理解
built on my Gestalt understanding from the memories that I have
现在 我可以根据真实数据
I can now actually create probability maps
创建受伤症状分布的概率图
of their distributions and
并将其公之于众
inform everybody based on real data
我也可以寻找有相似模式的患者
or I can look for similar patients who had similar patterns
并告诉他们在接受治疗时 什么对他们最有效
and say what works best with them when they were treated
以便更接近精准医疗
to try to get closer to precision medicine
整合大量的数据
Integrating the large amount of data
尝试探索我们过去的知 并尽你所能
and trying to exploit our past knowledge and to best inform how to
点明治疗病人的最佳方式
treat any individual the best you can
这对被送到医院的孩子意味着什么
What does that mean for the children that are brought to the hospital
Grant 医生说 ChRIS 平台
Dr. Grant says the ChRIS platform
能提供更有针对性的诊断和更个性化的护理
delivers more targeted diagnoses and more individualized care
如果我们拥有更复杂的数据库
If we have more complex databases
我们就能更好地理解信息之间繁杂的相互作用
we can understand complex interactions better
因此就能更好地指导每个患者
and hopefully guide individual patients better
我认为 ChRIS 就像是我
I think of ChRIS basically as my
进入超级大脑的接口
portal into multiple accessory lobes
它能让我比平时更聪明
so I can be a lot smarter than I can on my own
因为我不能一次把所有数据保存在我的大脑中
‘cause I cannot keep all this data in my brain at one time
当赌注如此沉重时
When the stakes are this high
我们要突破人类大脑的极限
we wanna push past the limits of the human brain
这位是 Máirín Duffy
Here's Máirín Duffy
她是红帽团队中的设计师 她让 ChRIS 成为现实
She's a designer on the Red Hat team that makes ChRIS happen
而根据个人经验 她知道这件事其中的风险
and she knows from personal experience what's at stake
我父亲中风了
My father had a stroke
所以我一直作为病人家属等待医疗技术诊断
so I've been there sort of in the patient's family side of waiting for medical technology
因为当一个人中风
‘cause when someone has a stroke
并被送到医院之后 医务人员必须弄清楚是哪种类型的中风
they bring you in the hospital and they have to figure out what type of stroke it is
根据中风类型 有不同的治疗方法
Based on the type, there's different treatments
如果使用了错误的治疗方案 就可能发生极其糟糕的事
If you give the wrong treatment, then really bad things can happen
所以 在这种情况下 你能越快地把病人送来做核磁共振
So, the faster you can get the patient in for an MRI
就能越快地得到治疗方案
the faster you can interpret the results in that situation
速度越快就有可能挽救他们的生命
The faster you can potentially save their life
想想看 仅仅是
Just think about just the fact of
把图像处理从云端推送出来
getting that image processing pushed out of the cloud
并行化处理 就能让它快很多
parallelized, make it so much faster
这样就能将这个过程从几小时 几天 缩短到几分钟
So instead of being hours or days, it's minutes
医学可能正迎来一个新的拐点
Medicine may be arriving at a new inflection point
一个不是由药理学驱动 而是由计算机科学驱动的拐点
One not driven by pharmacology, but by computer science
另外 想想像 ChRIS 这种东西的拓展性
Also, think about the scalability of something like ChRIS
发展中国家的医生也可以受益于
You could have doctors in developing countries benefiting
波士顿儿童医院的专业知识和数据集
from the expertise and data sets at Boston Children's Hospital
任何有手机服务的人都可以通过网络访问
Anybody with cell service could access web-based computing and data
能够拯救生命的数据和计算结果
that might save lives
除了医学
Besides medicine
很多其他领域也可能出现类似的拐点
lots of other fields could be witnessing a similar inflection point
但前提是 人们得知道如何从自己的数据中找到隐藏信息
But only if they figure out how to make their data collections sing
为了做到这一点 他们需要探索一个全新的计算领域
To do that, they need to discover a whole new territory of computing
世界各地的人们都在学习如何利用数据
All around the world, we're learning to make use of our data
就像在波士顿儿童医院一样
Diverting those data floods towards our own goals
将数据洪流导向目标
like at Boston Children's Hospital
换句话说 我们在处理这些数据
In other words, we're processing that data
但我们之所以能做到这一点
But we can only do that
是因为新一代的云计算使之成为可能
because a new generation of cloud-based computing makes the processing possible
对于像 ChRIS 这样的平台来说
For platforms like ChRIS
一个关键因素是
a key ingredient is that cloud-based computing
基于云计算的新型存储方式
is a new kind of storage
请记住 很多医院都会把收集到的数据扔掉
Remember that lots of hospitals throw out the data they gather
因为他们根本无法容纳所有数据
because they literally can't hold it all
这就是我想重点讨论的数据泛滥的最后一块拼图
That's what I wanna focus on as a last piece of the data flood puzzle
存储解决方案
The storage solution
对于 ChRIS 来说 存储解决方案是
For ChRIS, the storage solution
一个叫 Ceph 的开源项目
came in the form of an open source project called Ceph
它使用的马萨诸塞州开放云 就基于 Ceph
The Massachusetts Open Cloud, which ChRIS uses, depends on Ceph
我和 Ceph 的创造者 Sage Weil 聊了聊
So, I got chatting with its creator, Sage Weil
想了解更多关于像波士顿儿童医院这样的地方
to learn more about how places like Boston Children's
是如何以闪电般的速度处理海量数据的
can process enormous amounts of data in lightning time
以下是我与 Sage 的对话
Here's my conversation with Sage
我认为 第一个重要问题是
I think a great first question is
什么是 Ceph 它能做什么
what is Ceph and what does it do
当然 Ceph 是一个由软件定义的存储系统
Sure. Ceph is a software-defined storage system that
它允许你提供可靠的存储服务
allows you to provide a reliable storage service
并在不可靠的硬件上提供各种协议
providing various protocols across unreliable hardware
它的设计从开始就是满足可扩展性
It's designed from the ground up to be scalable
所以你可以拥有非常非常大的存储系统
so you can have very, very large storage systems
非常大的数据集
very large data sets
与此同时 系统对硬件故障和网络故障有优秀的容忍性
and you can make them available and tolerate hardware failures and network failures and so on
所以即使出现了一些这类问题
存储中的数据仍然不会变得难于访问
without compromising availability
现在 数据太多了
Nowadays, there's just so much data
是的
Yes
如此大的工作量 要处理的东西实在是太多了
So much consumption. There's just so much to get a handle on
是的
Yes
如此大的工作量 要处理的东西实在是太多了
So much consumption. There's just so much to get a handle on
你认为这个解决方案出现得是时候吗
Do you feel like the timing of it was part of the need for the solution
是的 肯定是这样 在当时 行业中
Yes, definitely. At the time, it just seemed
这方面的严重不足是显而易见的
painfully obvious that there's this huge gap in the industry
没有开源的解决方案可以
There was no open source solution
解决可扩展的存储问题
that would address the scalable storage problem
所以 我们显然得造个轮子
So it was obvious that we needed to build something
考虑到我们每天要处理的数据量
When we're thinking about the amount of data we're dealing with
on a daily basis and the fact that it's
以及它将来只会越来越多
only growing, it's only getting bigger
越来越难管理的事实 你认为当今该怎么做
and harder to manage
what do you see that's being worked on today
才能解决这种日益增长的需求
that will maybe address this growing need
我认为有几方面
I think there are sort of several pieces of it
一方面
The first thing is that
有令人难以置信的数据量正在产生
there's incredible amount of data being generated, of course
所以你需要可扩展的系统
so you need scalable systems that can
不仅可以在硬件和数据规模上进行扩展
scale not just in the amount of hardware and data that you're storing
而且 它的管理成本应该是一定的 至少应该基本固定
but also have a sort of fixed or nearly fixed operational overhead
嗯
Mm-hmm (affirmative)
你不会想就为每多 10PB 存储空间或类似的东西就多雇一个员工吧
You don't wanna pay another person per 10 petabytes or something like that
我认为这套系统在运维上也必须可扩展
So it has to be scalable. Operationally scalable, I guess would be the way to put it
是的
Yeah
这是其中的一部分 我认为
That's part of it. I think also the
人们利用存储空间的方式也在改变
way that people interact with storage is changing as well, so
一开始 都是文件存储
In the beginning, it was all file storage
然后我们有了虚拟机的块存储 我觉得对象存储
and then we have block storage for VMs, object storage is sort of
在某种程度上是行业的重要趋势
I think, a critical trend in the industry
我认为 下一个阶段的目标
I think really the next phase of this is
并不局限于提供一个对象存储端点
not so much around just providing an object storage endpoint
并将数据存储在集群中
and being able to store data in one cluster
我们需要将解决方案进一步升级
but really taking this sort of the level up
好让它能管理集群的集群
and having clusters of clusters
抑或是对分布于不同地理位置的
geographically distributed mesh of cloud footprints or
云空间及私有数据中心储存空间
private datacenter footprints where data is stored
中的数据进行管理
and being able to manage the data that's distributed across those
例如说 你现在将数据写入一个位置
Maybe you write the data today in one location
随着时间的推移 你可能会想将数据分层到到其他位置
you tier it off to somewhere else over time because it's
因为它更便宜 或者服务器离你更近 或者 一旦数据太老
cheaper, or it's closer, or the data's older
不会频繁使用了 你就需要将其移动到性能更低 容量更大的层次上
and you need to move it to a lower-performance, higher-capacity
以保证存储的成本较低
tier for pricing reasons
你可能也会为了遵循地方法规而移动数据
Dealing with things like compliance
在欧洲的一些地区接收数据时
so that when you ingest data in one
数据来源必须保持在
in Europe, it has to stay within
特定的政治边界内
certain political boundaries in order to comply with regulation
在某些行业 像 HIPAA 这样的东西
In certain industries, you have things like HIPAA that
HIPAA = 健康保险可携性和责任法案
1996 年在美国通过。规定了医疗和医保行业中个人身份信息应受保护。
限制了数据的移动方式 我认为 随着现代 IT 组织越来越多地
restricts the way that data's moved around. I think as modern IT organizations are
分布在不同的数据中心
increasingly spread across lots of different datacenters and lots of public clouds
公有和私有云中
and their own private cloud infrastructure
统一地 自动化地
being able to manage all this data and
管理它们的能力正变得越加重要
automate that management is becoming increasingly important
当你想到未来我们要如何管理和存储数据
When you think about how we're going to manage and store data
以及如何处理数据的时候
in the future, and process data in the future
开源在其中
how does open source
扮演了怎样的角色 你曾提到
play a role in that? You mentioned that you
你之所以要创建一个开源的解决方案 是因为你个人的理念
wanted to create an open source solution because of your personal philosophy and
和你对自由和开源软件的强烈感情
your strong feelings on free and open software
你如何看待开源对未来其他解决方案的影响
How do you see open source affecting other solutions in the future
我认为
I think that, um
特别是在基础设施领域
particularly in the infrastructure space
解决方案正在向开源靠拢
solutions are converging towards open source
我认为原因是基础设施领域的成本压力很大
I think the reason for that is there are high cost pressures in the infrastructure space
特别是对于构建
and particularly for people
软件即服务（SaaS）或云服务的人来说
building software-as-a-service or cloud services
低成本的基础设施很重要
it's important that they keep their infrastructure very cheap
从他们的角度来看 开源显然是一个非常好的方法
and open source is obviously a very good way to do that from their perspective
第二个原因更多地
And, I think the second reason is
是社会因素
more of a, I think, a social reason
在这个快速发展的领域里有如此多
and that it's such a fast-moving field where you have
新的工具 新的框架 新的协议 新的数据思维方式
new tools, new frameworks, new protocols new ways of thinking about data
这个领域中有这么多创新和变化
and there's so much innovation and change happening in that space
有这么多不同的产品
and so many different products and
和项目在相互作用
projects that are interacting, that it's very
所以很难以传统方式
hard to do that in a way that is
做到这一点 比如说
sort of based on the traditional model, where you have
让不同的公司互相签订合作协议 共同开发
different companies having partnership agreements and co-development or whatever
开源可以消除此事上的所有阻力
Open source removes all of that friction
Sage Weil 是红帽公司的高级咨询工程师
Sage Weil is a senior consulting engineer at Red Hat
也是 Ceph 项目的负责人
and the Ceph project lead
我要绕回到《经济学人》的 Kenneth Cukier
I'm gonna circle back to Kenneth Cukier from The Economist
以从一个更整体的视角上进行讨论
so we can zoom out a bit
因为我希望 我们能够记住他
because I want us to remember that vision he had
关于人与数据之间关系的看法
about our relationship with data
以及我们从泥板 到印刷机
and how we've progressed from clay tablets to the printing press
再到像 Sage 打造的云端奇迹的进步历程
to cloud-based wonders like the one Sage built
这关乎人类的进步
This is about human progress
关乎我们如何更好地理解世界
and it is about how we can understand the world
如何从现实中总结经验以及如何改善世界
and the empirical evidence of the world better to improve the world
这进步也是人类一直以来的使命
It is the same mission of progress that humans have always been on
使命永无止境
The mission never ends
但是 与此同时 学会处理我们收集到的数据
But, in the meantime, learning to process the data we've gathered
并将其投入使用 是整整一代人的开源任务
and put that flood to work
that's an open source mission for a whole generation
我们将在田纳西州的橡树岭国家实验室
We're ending our data journey with a quick stop
短暂停留 结束我们的数据之旅
at the Oak Ridge National Laboratory in Tennessee
它是世界上最快的超级计算机 Summit 的所在地
It's home to Summit, the world's fastest supercomputer
至少在 2018 年是最快的超级计算机
or at least fastest as of 2018
这台机器每秒能处理
This machine processes 200,000 trillion calculations
20 万亿次计算
per second
换个计量单位 就是 200 petaflops
That's 200 petaflops, if you're counting
这样的处理速度
Processing speed like that
对于医院、银行或者今天
isn't practical for hospitals or banks
所有受益于高性能计算的
or all the thousands of organizations
成千上万的组织来说并不现实
that benefit from high high performance computing today
像 Summit 这样的超级计算机
Supercomputers like Summit
更多的是留给强子对撞机的领域
are reserved more for Hadron Collider territory
不过话说回来
But then again
我们曾经在泥板上记录的只是 100 字节的信息
we were once recording just a hundred bytes of info on clay tablets
在数据存储和数据处理的领域中
The story of data storage and data processing
非凡的壮举不断成为新的常态
is one where extraordinary feats
keep becoming the new normal
有一天 我们或许能将 Summit 级别的超级计算机装进口袋
One day, we might all have Summit-sized supercomputers in our pockets.
想一想 到时候我们能够搜索到的答案
Think of the answers we'll be able to search for then
下一集 我们聊聊无服务器
Next episode, we're going serverless
或者 真的没服务器吗
Or are we
第 7 集将会讲述我们与基于云的开发之间
Episode 7 is all about our evolving relationship
不断发展的关系
with cloud-based development
我们将会探究 在我们的工作中有
We're figuring out how much of our work we can abstract
多少可以抽象化的部分 以及在这个过程可能会失去的东西
and what we might be giving up in the process
同时 如果你想深入了 ChRIS 的故事
Meantime, if you wanna dive deeper into the ChRIS story
请访问 redhat.com/chris
visit redhat.com/chris
了解它是如何构建的
to learn more about how it was built
以及如何为项目本身做出贡献
and how you can contribute to the project itself
《代码英雄》是一款红帽公司原创的播客
Command Line Heroes is an original podcast from Red Hat
你可以在苹果播客、谷歌播客
Listen for free on Apple Podcasts, Google Podcasts
或任何你喜欢的平台上免费收听
or wherever you do your thing
我是 Saron Yitbarek 坚持编程 下期再见
I'm Saron Yitbarek. Until next time, keep on coding